Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ charleneplaton (LinkedIn) www.charleneplaton.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Nursing

PowerPoint

Languages

Spanish (Professional Working) English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Design Kit: The Course for Human-Centered Design

Family Nurse Practitioner (FNP-BC)

Leading in Health Systems: Integrating Effort, Improving Outcomes

The Leadership Conversation: Creating Leadership

Public Health Nurse (PHN)

Honors-Awards

8th Annual Debbie Wilson Memorial Student Scholarship

Leslie Ann Ferree Memorial Compassion Award

Certificate of Achievement, RN Residency

Recognition for Creative Contribution Volunteer Spotlight

Charlene Platon

Director of Ambulatory Nursing at Stanford Health Care | Johnson & Johnson Nurse Innovation Fellow

Redwood City, California

Summary

I am an energetic, motivated self-starter with administrative and clinical experience, and a passion for continuous improvement and innovation. Currently, I am Director of Ambulatory Nursing at Stanford Health Care, and am one of 12 inaugural Johnson & Johnson Nurse Innovation Fellows. I am a board-certified family nurse practitioner and licensed registered nurse.

My goal is to transform healthcare delivery and operations at the intersection of compassion, innovation, and technology, ultimately improving the healthcare experience for patients and professionals. I am especially passionate about utilizing creativity and interdisciplinary collaboration to address organizational and industry-wide problems.

StandOut Strengths Roles: Creator and Teacher

Experience

Stanford Health Care 3 years 11 months

Director, Ambulatory Nursing April 2020 - Present (4 months)

Stanford, California, United States

The Director of Ambulatory Nursing provides leadership for advancing, developing, refining, and innovating nursing clinical delivery operations across all Stanford Health Care ambulatory practice areas.

Specialty Coordinator, APP Administrative Fellowship September 2019 - April 2020 (8 months)

Stanford, California, United States

The Advanced Practice Provider (APP) Administrative Fellowship prepares clinical experts to successfully transition to a healthcare leadership role by immersing in health care operations, project development, and people

management experiences. The program's goal is to provide the Fellow with an invaluable experience in advanced practice operations through exposure to APP administration and meaningful project work.

Manager of Advanced Practice, Center for Advanced Practice September 2016 - April 2020 (3 years 8 months)

Stanford, California, United States

The Center for Advanced Practice at Stanford Health Care is dedicated to promoting the role of the Advanced Practice Provider (APP) within SHC as well as the medical community at large. Advanced Practice Provider roles include: physician assistants (PAs), nurse practitioners (NPs), certified registered nurse anesthetists (CRNAs), and clinical nurse specialists (CNSs). APPs are medical providers who are able to treat, diagnose, prescribe, and perform or assist in surgical procedures in collaboration with physicians.

Johnson & Johnson Nurse Innovation Fellow October 2019 - Present (10 months)

Johnson & Johnson has partnered with the Center for Creative Leadership (CCL) and Nurse Approved to launch the Nurse Innovation Fellowship. The goal of the Fellowship is to develop the leadership and entrepreneurial ability of nurses, ultimately promoting nurse-led innovation in healthcare across the global stage. In the two-year program, Fellows receive individualized mentoring, complete projects, and strengthen their leadership, entrepreneurial and innovation skills. I am honored to be selected as one of 12 inaugural Johnson & Johnson Nurse Innovation Fellows.

https://nursing.jnj.com/innovate-with-us/nurse-fellowship

UC Irvine

Lead Student Manager, DVT Mobile Application Development September 2015 - June 2016 (10 months)

Irvine, CA

Directed and collaborated with other students in nursing, public health, and computer engineering degrees to develop web-based smartphone application, "My Happy Blood," to improve outpatient warfarin and blood thinner management.

Adventist Health White Memorial Charitable Foundation Registered Nurse

March 2013 - September 2015 (2 years 7 months)

Los Angeles, CA

Staff registered nurse in the telemetry/critical care extension unit (CCU), with experience floating to the cardiovascular definitive observation unit, intensive care unit, and stroke unit. Graduated from a comprehensive 18-week Versant RN residency, as well as a 5-week orientation in the intensive care unit. Coordinated and monitored CCU as Lead Nurse when needed, troubleshooting unit-based issues.

Leadership/Ancillary Positions:

- Coordinator, Hospital-Wide SWAT RN Team
- Hospital-Certified Spanish Interpreter
- Secretary, Nursing Practice Council (Shared Governance Model)
- Co-Chairperson, CCU/DOU Unit-Based Council
- Member, Throughput Committee

Illumination Foundation
Recuperative Care RN Medical Coordinator
July 2012 - February 2013 (8 months)
Costa Mesa, CA

Managed the discharge process of homeless clients from LA and OC hospitals to Recuperative Care Center, ensuring clients were discharged with appropriate medications and medical supplies. Executed nursing model for transitional care, connecting clients to comprehensive medical and social services including housing placement, enrollment in medical insurance (Medical and Medicare), and relevant home health/ancillary care.

Developed Recuperative Care Medical Coordinator Handbook, organizing policies and procedures of the position and streamlining processes to improve Medical Coordinator efficiency, and enhance new-hire orientation and training.

UCI Health

Senior Hospital Assistant April 2010 - December 2010 (9 months)

Assisted interdisciplinary hospital staff with patient care responsibilities and clerical duties. Facilitated nursing assistant documentation by implementing "SHA Daily Worksheet".

COPE Health Solutions
Clinical Care Extender
August 2008 - July 2009 (1 year)

Orange County, California Area

Achieved 240+ service hours in telemetry, orthopedics, gynecology/urology, and labor & delivery. Supported patients with meals, hygiene, elimination, and necessary activities of daily living.

Education

Stanford Continuing Studies
Accelerate Your Startup Idea · (2020)

University of California, Irvine – Sue & Bill Gross School of Nursing Master of Science (M.S.), Nursing Science (Family Nurse Practitioner Concentration)

University of California, Irvine – Sue & Bill Gross School of Nursing Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Nursing Science

Spanish55 - Language and Cross-Cultural Coaching (2015 - 2016)